Preliminary Inventory to the George Davis Herron Papers, 1916-1927
Hoover Institution Archives
George Davis Herron Papers,
1916-1927
23002
Herron, George Davis, 1862-1925
16 volumes, 30 manuscript boxes, 4 scrapbooks, 2 microfilm reels (20.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, interviews, lectures, essays, notes, and clippings, relating to the League of Nations, territorial quesions, prisoners of war, and other political and economic issues at the Paris Peace Conference.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; League of Nations; Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920); Peace; Prisoners of war; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918 -- Germany; World War, 1914-1918 -- Peace; World War, 1914-1918 -- Prisoners and prisons; World War, 1914-1918 -- Territorial questions; Germany; United States -- Foreign relations
Container List
- BOUND VOLUMES (on shelf)
  - Volume I. Germany-1
    - Letter to Mr. W.F. Sharp, American Ambassador in Paris, 1917 December 5 (Item I)
    - Second letter to Sharp, 1917 December 28 (Item II)
    - Letter from Mr. Sharp to Herron, 1918 January 17 (Item III)
    - From Mr. H.R. Wilson, American Legation, Bern, 1918 January 24 (Item IV)
    - Legation Report of conversation between Herron and Muehlon, 1918 February 12 (Item V)
    - Conversation with Conrad Haussmann, 1918 February 14 (Item VI)
    - Letter of Haussmann to Dr. van Beek en Donk, 1918 February 16 (Item VI A)
    - Document by Muehlon handed to Herron, 1918 February 17 (Item VI B)
    - Letter addressed by Prince Max von Baden to Prince Alexander Hohenlohe; furnished to Herron by Muehlon, 1918 February 17 (Item VI C)
    - Letter of Herron to Wilson concerning message of Muehlon, 1918 February 18 (Item VII)
    - Letter from Dr. Fred Perrière, International Committee of the Red Cross, to Herron concerning information that follows, 1918 February 12 (Item VIII)
    - Letter of Professor Staudinger to Dr. Perrière referred to in document, 1918 February 1 (Item VIII A)
    - Second letter of Professor Staudinger to Dr. Perrière, 1918 February 8 (Item VIII B)
    - Conversations between Count Montgelas and Herron, 1918 February 28 (Item IX)
    - Second conversation with Montgelas, 1918 March 1 (Item X)
    - Concerning telegram of Lammasch (telegram is in Austrian documents), 1918 March 11 (Item XI)
    - Concerning German peace messengers, 1918 March 12 (Item XII)
    - Conversations between Herron and Professor Edgar Jaffé of the University of Munich, 1918 March 26 (Item XIII)
    - Conversation with Professor Quidde, 1918 April 19 (Item XIV)
    - Concerning ostensible interview in "Daily Mail"; conversation with Professor Delmar, 1918 May 11 (Item XV)
    - Explanation of Commander Whittall concerning the same, 1918 May 14 (Item XVI)
    - Confidential letter from Professor Bauer, University of Basel, regarding possible German invasion of Switzerland, 1918 May 22 (Item XVII)
    - British Foreign Office and Quidde interview, 1918 May 23 (Item XVIII)
    - Letter from de Yong van Beek en Donk concerning the interview, 1918 May 23 (Item XIX)
    - Reply of Herron to Van Beek en Donk, 1918 May 24 (Item XX)
    - Herron to Wilson concerning Bauer's letter, 1918 May 27 (Item XXI)
    - Letter of Foerster to Muehlon concerning German peace conditions, 1918 June 4 (Item XXII)
    - Translation of Foerster's letter to Muehlon, 1918 June 4 (Item XXIII)
    - Herron to Wilson on current matters, 1918 June 6 (Item XXIV)
    - Beginning of Bavarian conversations between Dr. de Fiori and Herron, 1918 May 8, June 5 (Item XXV)
    - A new German peace initiative; First conversation between de Fiori and Herron, 1918 June 14 (Item XXV A)
    - Continuation of the same. Conversations stenographically taken down and verified by both de Fiori and Herron (Item XXV B)
    - Continuation of the same, 1918 June 27 (Item XXV C)
    - Conversation between de Fiori and Professor Bernard Jasink, 1918 July 7 (Item XXV D)
    - Second series of conversations with Dr. de Fiori, 1918 July 8-12 (Item XXV E)
    - Third series of conversations with de Fiori, 1918 July 16 (Item XXV F)
    - Fourth visit of Dr. de Fiori, 1918 September 10 (Item XXV G)
    - Letter of Herron to Bland enclosing report of de Fiori's fourth visit, for British Foreign Office, 1918 September 12 (Item XXV H)
    - Letter to Mr. Sharp, American Ambassador in Paris (Item XXV I)
    - Herron to Minister Stovall, Bern, 1918 September 14 (Item XXV K)
    - A last appeal to Germany. Fifth visit of Dr. de Fiori, 1918 October 25 (Item XXV L)
    - Letter from Dr. de Fiori to Herron, 1918 November 4 (Item XXV M)
    - A note concerning the above letter, included in next report (Item XXV N)
    - Dr. de Fiori's last appeal and fifth visit, 1918 November 4 (Item XXV O)
    - Telegram from de Fiori to Herron, 1918 November 11 (Item XXV P)
    - Letter from de Fiori to Herron, 1918 November 24 (Item XXV Q)
    - Letter from Herron, replying to above, 1918 December 2 (Item XXV R)
    - Letter from de Fiori to Herron, 1918 December 21 (Item XXV S)
    - Addendum to reports of the Bavarian Initiative, 1918 December 23 (Item XXV T)
    - Concerning a Papal initiative of peace negotiations, 1918 July 1 (Item XXVI)
  - Volume II. Germany-2
    - Concerning Admiral Hintze, the new German Foreign Minister, 1918 July 11 (Item XXVII)
    - Letter of Bland to Herron, 1918 July 12 (Item XXVIII)
    - Conversations with Professor Singer and Professor Jasink, 1918 July 20 (Item XXIX)
    - Letter of Herron to Bland, 1918 July 21 (Item XXX)
    - Letter of Herron to Bland (Item XXXI)
    - Report mentioned above (Item XXXI A)
    - Memorandum, 1918 July 8 (Item XXXI B)
    - Letter from Bland to Herron, 1918 July 30 (Item XXXII)
    - Letter from Professor Hertz in Vienna to Herron, 1918 August 4 (Item XXXIII)
    - Letter of Herron to Bland concerning Muehlon, 1918 August 5 (Item XXXIV)
    - Other letter of Herron to Bland, 1918 August 5 (Item XXXV)
    - Herron to Troelstra, 1918 August 17 (Item XXXVI)
    - Troelstra to Herron (Item XXXVII)
    - Report to State Department concerning Troelstra's mission to Switzerland, 1918 August 26 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Letter of Herron to Bland, 1918 August 27 (Item XXXIX)
    - Troelstra to Herron, 1918 August 27 (Item XL)
    - Herron to Troelstra, 1918 August 29 (Item XLI)
    - Second report to State Department concerning Troelstra, 1918 August 29 (Item XLII)
    - Letter from Count Montgelas to Herron, 1918 August 28 (Item XLIII)
    - Concerning Troelstra's mission. Report of a friend of Sir H. Whittall's who visited Troelstra with letter of introduction from Herron (Item XLIV)
    - Memorandum of Troelstra sent to Herron by the aforesaid British visitor, 1918 September 3 (Item XLV)
    - Report to State Department summing up Troelstra's activities in Switzerland, 1918 September 6 (Item XLVI)
    - Memorandum, 1918 September 7 (Item XLVI A)
    - Report about German conditions, 1918 September 9 (Item XLVII)
    - Troelstra to Herron, 1918 September 8 (Item XLVIII)
    - Exit Troelstra 1918 September 14 (Item XLIX)
    - Herron to Troelstra, 1918 September 17 (Item L)
    - Letter of Herron to Ambassador Sharp, Paris, enclosing a memorandum, 1918 September 14 (Item LI)
    - Report to State Department, 1918 September 24 (Item LII)
    - Report to State Department, 1918 October (Early) (Item LIII)
    - Conversation with Professor Seiler, Berne Medical College, 1918 October 9 (Item LIV)
    - Visit of Professor Nippold, 1918 October 15 (Item LV)
    - Memorandum to State Department, 1918 October 22 (Item LVI)
    - Memorandum to President Wilson, 1918 October 22 (Item LVII)
    - Herron to Jasink, 1918 October 24 (Item LVIII)
    - Herron to "Le Journal de Genève," 1918 October 26 (Item LVIII A)
    - Herron to de Benedetti, 1918 October 26 (Item LVIII B)
    - Telegram of Herron to de Benedetti, 1918 October 27 (Item LIX)
    - Letter of Foerster to Herron, 1918 October 28 (Item LX)
    - Reply of Herron to Foerster, 1918 November 2 (Item LXI)
    - Herron to State Department, 1918 November 1 (Item LXII)
    - Telegram of Kurt Eisner to Herron, 1918 November 10 (Item LXIII)
    - Eisner to Herron (Item LXIII A)
    - Telegram from Jaffé to Herron, 1918 November 10 (Item LXIV)
    - Translation of above telegram (Item LXIV A)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1918 November 12 (Item LXV)
    - Herron to Eisner and Jaffé (Item LXVI)
    - Translation of foregoing telegram (Item LXVI A)
    - Other telegram of Herron to Jaffé concerning armistice, 1918 November 14 (Item LXVII)
    - German translation of the same (Item LXVIII)
    - Jaffé to Herron; telegram from Jaffé to Herron in response to foregoing, 1918 November 18 (Item LXIX)
    - Translation of Jaffé's telegram (Item LXIX A)
    - Telegram from Jaffé to Heron. Inquiry about Ismeth Bey, 1918 November 19 (Item LXX)
    - Reply of Herron to the same, 1918 November 20 (Item LXXI)
    - Herron to Colonel Godson, Intelligence Officer American Army in Switzerland, 1918 November 18 (Item LXXII)
    - Letter of Professor Hertz to Herron, 1918 November 14 (Item LXXIII)
    - Reply of Herron to the foregoing, 1918 November 18 (Item LXXIV)
    - Report to State Department on German appeals, 1918 November 17 (Item LXXV)
    - Herron to Stovall, reporting telegram of Walter Rathenau to friend in Switzerland, 1918 November 18 (Item LXXVI)
    - Herron to British Foreign Office reporting same telegram, 1918 November 18 (Item LXXVII)
    - British Consul General in Zurich to Herron enclosing copy of article in "Muenchener Neueste Kachrichten," 1918 November 23 (Item LXXVIII)
    - Copy of above article, "Ein amerikanisches Friedensangebot" by Jaffé (Item LXXVIII A)
    - Letter of Herron to British Consul General, 1918 November 25 (Item LXXIX)
    - To "Journal de Genève," in answer to their inquiry about the above, 1918 November 26 (Item LXXX)
    - Statement of Herron to representative of "Berliner Tageblatt," 1918 November 26 (Item LXXXI)
    - "Muenchener Neueste Nachrichten." Copy of paper containing above article, 1918 November 27 (Item LXXXII)
    - Colonel MacHugh (successor to Sir Hugh Whittall as chief of British Intelligence Service) to Herron, 1918 November 27 (Item LXXXIII)
    - Herron to Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 November 30 (Item LXXXIV)
    - From Count Montgelas to Herron, 1918 November 22 (Item LXXXV)
    - From Herron to Count Montgelas, 1918 November 27 (Item LXXXVI)
    - Professor Hertz to Herron. Telegram asking for appointment (Item LXXXVII)
    - Professor Delmar to Herron. Telegram; impending famine in Germany and need for immediate help from Allies; commission to investigate (German), 1918 November 24 (Item LXXXVIII)
    - Delmar to Herron, 1918 November 25 (Item LXXXIX)
    - Memorandum to the State Department, 1918 November 27 (Item XC)
    - Count Montgelas to Herron, 1918 December 1 (Item XCI)
    - Foerster to Herron, 1918 December 17 (Item XCII)
    - Herron to Foerster, 1918 December 25 (Item XCIII)
    - Memorandum to the State Department, 1918 December 20 (Item XCIV)
    - Sent by Foerster to Herron. Address of Foerster to Delegates of German Soldiers assembled in Berlin and referred to in preceding memorandum, 1918 December 20 (Item XCV)
    - Colonel House to Herron. Referring to letter of Colonel MacHugh, 1918 December 21 (Item XCVI)
    - A note of appeal to the President, 1918 December 22 (Item XCVII)
    - Report made by Mr. Horneffer of the International Red Cross, 1919 January 4 (Item XCVIII)
    - Memorandum to State Department, 1919 January 5 (Item XCIX)
    - Memorandum to State Department, 1919 January 8 (Item C)
    - Addendum to preceding memorandum on Pan-Germanism and Bolshevism, 1919 January 15 (Item CI)
    - Schlieben to Herron. German original of letter quoted in preceding memorandum, 1919 January 13 (Item CII)
    - Dispatch mentioned in above memorandum, 1919 January 4 (Item CIII)
    - Herron to "Neue Freie Press," 1919 January 13 (Item CIV)
    - Allen W. Dulles to Herron concerning Muehlon's view of Germany, 1919 January 15 (Item CV)
    - Memorandum addressed to Herron by Bernstein, Foerster, Muehlon, Schlieben and Ball, 1919 February 10 (Item CVI)
    - Germany's Eleventh Hour; Memorandum of Herron to American Peace Commissioners in Paris, 1919 February 12 (Item CVII)
    - Letter of Herron to House enclosing memorandum, 1919 March 2 (Item CVIII)
    - Herron to Stovall, 1919 March 22 (Item CIX)
    - House to Herron. Acknowledging letter of March 23rd and memorandum by Wrangel, 1919 March 28 (Item CX)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 May 14 (Item CXI)
    - Herron to House. Giving copy of letter from Count Montgelas concerning his disappointment in the Peace Conference and in President Wilson, 1919 May 15 (Item CXII)
    - Montgelas to Herron. Letter reported to House in preceding document (Item CXII A)
    - German original of letter reported to above (Item CXII B)
    - Herron to Montgelas. Acknowledging above letter which has been sent to Colonel House and Sir W. Tyrell terms which Germany would have imposed had she been victorious; and terms imposed on Roumania (Item CXIII)
    - Herron to Sir W. Tyrell (now Secretary General British Peace Delegation) enclosing letter of Montgelas (Item CXIV)
    - House to Herron concerning Herron's reply to Montgelas, 1919 May 18 (Item CXV)
    - Herron to President Wilson. Telegram on determination of German Government to declare bankruptcy if treaty is rejected; consequences of this act, 1919 November 24 (Item CXVI)
  - Volume III. Austria-1
    - Herron to Hugh Wilson for State Department, 1918 January 25 (Item I)
    - Telegram from Meinl, Vienna, to Herron, sent through de Yonk van Beek en Donk, 1918 January 29 (Item II)
    - Telegram from Meinl to van Beek en Donk for Herron, 1918 January 29 (Item III)
    - Memorandum of conversation between Lammasch and Herron, verbally reported by Herron to Wilson, immediately following the conversation, and stenographically taken down and dispatched in code by Wilson to State Department, 1918 February 3 (Item IV)
    - Conversation between Muehlon and Herron, 1918 February 3 (Item IV A)
    - Second conversation between Herron and Lammasch, 1918 February 4 (Item V)
    - Statement of Dr. Muehlon referred to above (Item V A)
    - Report to the State Department, concerning conversations between Herron and Lammasch, 1918 February 7 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Wilson regarding mission, 1918 February 17 (Item VII)
    - Letter from Lammasch to Herron praying for the success of our negotiations, 1918 February 9 (Item VIII)
    - Telegram from Lammasch for Herron, sent through van Beek en Donk conveying Emperor's acceptance of Mr. Herron's propositions, 1918 February 18 (Item IX)
    - Translation of foregoing telegram (Item IX A)
    - De Yong van Beek en Donk to Herron forwarding copy of telegram from Lammasch; suggesting meeting with Meinl, 1918 February 18 (Item X)
    - Code telegram from Herron to Meinl, sent through de Yong van Beek en Donk; date missing, but certainly between February 18 and 21, while the decision of Emperor Charles was still pending (Item XI)
    - Translation into German of above telegram (Item XI A)
    - Code telegram from Lammasch and Meinl to Herron, sent through de Yong (Item XII)
    - Herron to Dolbeare enclosing preceding telegram, 1918 February 28 (Item XIII)
    - Herron to Hugh R. Wilson for the State Department, 1918 February 28 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1918 March 1 (Item XV)
    - Lammasch to de Yong van Beek en Donk for Herron, 1918 March 6 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1918 March 11 (Item XVII)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1918 March 18 (Item XVIII)
    - Herron to Wilson for State Department, 1918 April 11 (Item XIX)
    - Herron to Wilson for State Department, 1918 April 11 (Item XX)
    - A communication by one of the chiefs of the Swiss Political Department to the Swiss Federal Government, 1918 April 14. A copy of this was obtained by Herron and given to Wilson to forward by code to Washington (Item XXI)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1918 April 16 (Item XXII)
    - Herron to Wilson for State Department, 1918 April 16 (Item XXIII)
    - Report of a purported interview of Herron by an Austro-Italian journalist of the name of Flesch, a member of the Italian Press Bureau in Berne (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Wilson for State Department, 1918 April 19 (Item XXV)
    - Letter from Mr. Sautter to Pasteur Ferrière, 1918 April 19 (Item XXVI)
    - Sautter to Herron, 1918 April 25 (Item XXVII)
    - Second letter of Sautter to Herron, 1918 April 30 (Item XXVIII)
    - Herron to Wilson for State Department, 1918 May 3 (Item XXIX)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1918 May 6 (Item XXX)
    - Herron to Dr. de Yong for Professor Lammasch, 1918 May 7 (Item XXXI)
    - Herron to Wilson for State Department, 1918 July 20 (Item XXXII)
    - Telegram of Herron to President Wilson, 1918 September 17 (Item XXXIII)
    - Herron to Bland, British Foreign Office, for Mr. Balfour, 1918 September 17 (Item XXXIV)
    - Dr. Hertz to Herron. Enclosing translation of propositions; asking for typewritten copy, 1918 September 29 (Item XXXV)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1918 October 2 (Item XXXVI)
    - The Hertz Memorandum referred to at the beginning of preceding letter (Item XXXVII)
    - Herron to State Department, 1918 October 3 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Second visit of Dr. Hertz to Herron, 1918 October 5 (Item XXXIX)
    - Memorandum of Herron to State Department, 1918 October 7 (Item XL)
    - Dr. de Yong van Beek en Donk to Herron, 1918 October 9 (Item XLI)
    - Telegram of Herron to The President giving copy and translation of a telegram from Professor Lammasch about acceptance of 10th Point, 1918 October 14 (Item XLII)
    - Memorandum to State Department, 1918 November 22 (Item XLIII)
    - Memorandum to State Department. "Immediate Austria," 1918 December 30 (Item XLIV)
    - Dr. Ferrière to Herron enclosing a letter suggesting that it might be laid before the American Peace Commission. In French, 1919 January 16 (Item XLV)
    - Translation of foregoing letter (Item XLV A)
    - Letter of Dr. Johann Thiel to Dr. Ferrière, 1918 December 29 (Item XLV B)
    - Translation of preceding letter (Item XLV C)
  - Volume IV. Austria-2
    - Herron to Legation. Forwarding copy of preceding letter from Dr. Ferrière and Johann Thiel, 1919 January 18 (Item XLVI)
    - Herron to State Department, 1919 February 5 (Item XLVII)
    - Herron to State Department, 1919 February 5 (Item XLVII A)
    - Herron to Lansing, 1919 February 5 (Item XLVIII)
    - Headlam-Morley to Herron. Acknowledging copy of Dr. Ferrière's letter, 1919 February 6 (Item XLIX)
    - Dr. Louis Ferrière to Herron, 1919 February 12 (Item L)
    - Herron to House. Enclosing memorandum of Dr. Louis Ferrière, 1919 February 18 (Item LI)
    - Memorandum from the Comité International de Secours pour les Enfants, 1919 April 2 (Item LII)
    - Lazlo Havas to Herron, 1919 April 21 (Item LIII)
    - Lammasch to Herron, 1919 April 8. Appealing for occupation by Allied troops; need of immediate help (Item LIV)
    - Lammasch to Herron. Same subject as preceding letter, 1919 April 8 (Item LV)
    - Herron to The President. Enclosing Lammasch's letter, 1919 April 10 (Item LV A)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrell. Same, 1919 April 10 (Item LV B)
    - Herron to William Martin. Same, 1919 April 10 (Item LV C)
    - Herron to Minister Stowall. Same, 1919 April 10 (Item LV D)
    - Herron to Lammasch. Referring to telegram sent by Herron to The President, 1919 April 10 (Item LV E)
    - Minister Stowall to Herron. Concerning Professor Lammasch's appeal, 1919 April 12 (Item LVI)
    - Lammasch to Herron. His illness; diminishing hope of outside help for Austria, 1919 April 13 (Item LVII)
    - Herron to Lammasch. Acknowledgment received of telegram to President; "Geleitwort" to works of President, 1919 April 14 (Item LVIII)
    - Confidential Secretary of the President to Herron. Acknowledging telegram and letter concerning Lammasch, 1919 April 15 (Item LIX)
    - Lammasch to Herron. His revived hopes for Austria; reasons why Austria should have different treatment than Germany, 1919 April 22 (Item LX)
    - Herron to Lammasch. Responding to preceding letter, 1919 April 23 (Item LXI)
    - Herron to The President. Enclosing Lammasch's appeal, 1919 April 23 (Item LXII)
    - Lammasch to Herron. Enclosing memorandum concerning Southern Tyrol for President Wilson; also acknowledging introduction to Marquis Paulucci; Italy's Ambassador to Berne, 1919 May 4 (Item LXIII)
    - Herron to Dulles. Enclosing Tyrol Memorandum sent by Lammasch, 1919 April 26 (Item LXIV)
    - Herron to Sir W. Tyrell. Enclosing appeal of Professor Lammasch, 1919 April 23 (Item LXIV A)
    - Herron to Lammasch. Forebodings as to disastrous outcome of Peace Conference, 1919 April 26 (Item LXV)
    - Lammasch to Herron. Southern Tyrol and decision of Peace Conference; importance of settlement to France and England; relations with Italy; plebiscite, 1919 April 27 (Item LXVI)
    - Herron to Sir W. Tyrell. Enclosing letter of Lammasch, 1919 April 29 (Item LXVII)
    - Lammasch to Herron, 1919 April 29 (Item LXVIII)
    - Herron to Lammasch. Reporting that Lammasch's appeal has been sent to President Wilson by special courier, 1919 May 1 (Item LXIX)
    - Herron to The President. Courier letter enclosing Lammasch's appeal, 1919 May 1 (Item LXX)
    - Lammasch to Herron, 1919 May 3 (Item LXXI)
    - Herron to The President, 1919 May 6 (Item LXXII)
    - Lammasch to Herron. From St. Germain; concerning conditions at Peace Conference, 1919 May 19 (Item LXXIII)
    - Lammasch to Herron. Concerning cruel deceptions at Paris, 1919 June 3 (Item LXXIV)
    - Lammasch to Herron. His departure from St. Germain; loss of faith in President Wilson, 1919 June 15 (Item LXXV)
    - Pasteur Ferrière to Herron. Enclosing letter of Dr. Ferrière from Paris, 1919 June 15 (Item LXXVI)
    - Letter of Dr. Ferrière referred to in preceding letter, 1919 June 11 (Item LXXVII)
    - Lammasch to Herron. Possible understanding with Italy; suggested concessions; Southern Tyrol; Austria's value to the world; no longer hope of Danubian Confederation, 1919 June 24 (Item LXXVIII)
    - Hertz to Herron. Acknowledging letter; forwarding copies of paper asked for; basis of peace settlement wrong; suggested understanding between Austria and Italy, 1919 June 24 (Item LXXIX)
    - Telegram. Herron to Lammasch. Giving requested address of Dr. Ferrière (Item LXXX)
    - Hertz to Herron. Enclosing article regarding Austria; request that it my be placed before Peace Commissioners, 1919 August 13 (Item LXXXI)
    - Herron to Hertz. Acknowledging report; forwarding letters from Americans, 1919 August 19 (Item LXXXII)
    - Herron to Polk. Forwarding report of Dr. Hertz, 1919 August 19 (Item LXXXIII)
    - Hertz to Herron. Enclosing copy of article on Peace Terms, 1919 August 21 (Item LXXXIV)
    - Herron to House. Asking that Article No. 201 in the Austrian Peace Treaty may be abolished and finance left to Reparation Committee, 1919 August 30 (Item LXXXV)
    - Weiser to Herron. His meeting with Dr. Saffer; Austrian Peace Treaty and appeal to Colonel House, 1919 August 30 (Item LXXXVI)
    - Telegram from Lammasch to Herron. Concerning sending of express letter; suggesting that Herron should see Paulucci, 1919 September 3 (Item LXXXVII)